Contact Info

Karachi, Sindh Pakistan furqan.malickoffical@gmail.com 03338591535

Education

University Of Karachi

Karachi / Masters in Human Resource Management HRM (Waiting For Result) (2024)

University Of Karachi

Karachi / Bachelors in Sociology Sociology (2022) 70%

Skills

TIME MANAGEMENT LEADERSHIP PROBLEM SOLVING



Certifications

- Information Security
 Habib Metro Bank | 2024
- Basic Concepts of Islamic Banking
 Habib Metro Bank | 2024
- Fair Treatment to Customers
 Curricula

Habib Metro Bank | 2024

- Fraud Risk Awareness
 Habib Metro Bank | 2024
- Business Continuity
 Management
 Habib Metro Bank | 2024
- Information Security
 Habib Metro Bank | 2023
- Diversity, Equity & Inclusion Habib Metro Bank | 2023
- MS Office
 SARDAR YASIN MALIK
 UNIVERSITY OF KARACHI | 2021
- LEARNING AND DEVELOPMENT United Bank Limited | 2015

Furqan Malick

Digital Service Monitoring Unit ADC- Operation at Habib Metro Bank



Summary

Dedicated analyst with exceptional problem-solving ability and critical thinking skills. Experience with numerous aspects of financial and intelligence analysis, including use of open-source and proprietary software to perform statistical calculations and model data and projections.

Work Experience

Digital Service Monitoring Unit ADC- Operation HABIB METRO BANK

15 months

Karachi, Pakistan | Oct 2023 - Present

Major Responsibilities:

- Actively monitor 24/7 installed ATMs (on-site or off-site) performance and up time.
- Follow up with vendors for ATM Complaints.
- Resolution of ATM Complaints in System on daily basis.
- Responsible for timely resolving SBP ATM related Complaints if any reported.
- Responsible for timely reporting to SBP on daily basis in holidays.
- Responsible for timely reporting to SBP on Raast Transactions Financial Reoprts.
- Responsible for ATMs MIS Reports (Weekly Downtime report, ATM Downtime to branch, Transaction Report, etc.)
- Monitoring of ATMs through (isuite NCR- Vynamic View Wincore/Diebold), provide first level support to the branches regarding ATM issues and coordinate with branches, vendors and different departments of HabibMetro Bank for smooth working of ATM Operations.
- Call logging and follow up with vendors (NCR and Wincore/Diebold) for ATM's Complaints.
- Coordinating with Network team for support of connectivity Complaints resolution to minimize impact to customers and internal users in coordination with end users, team members, management, vendors, and other internal IT teams.
- Responsible for monitoring of ATM network cash floats, attending to ATM Faults, coordinating for cash replenishment and ensuring ATM uptime is maintained at all times.

Digital Customer Care Analyst

UNITED BANK LIMITED

Karachi, Pakistan | Dec 2019 - Feb 2021

Knowledge of customer service practices:

- customers' questions and concerns and provide answers or responses.
- Provide information about products and services.
- Take orders, calculate charges, and process billing or payments.
- Review customer accounts and make changes, if necessary.
- Handle returns or complaints.
- Experience with ALTITUDE, GNP, AVAYA,

14 months

Languages

• English & Urdu - Medium

Hobbies

• Driving Gyming & Sports.

EBS, CRN, PRIME.

Customer Services (MRCB) UNITED BANK LIMITED

Karachi, Pakistan | Mar 2015 - Oct 2016 Email support representative:

- Proficient in Microsoft Office
- Knowledge of customer service practices
- Experience in mediation and conflict
- resolution techniques
- Data analysis experience
- Knowledge of research practices
- Experience with ALTITUDE, GNP, AVAYA,
- EBS, CRN.

19 months